alamy.com 2000-12-08

# alamy.com - security and privacy

At alamy.com we take your security and privacy very seriously and we aim to make your experience with us entirely safe and problem free. Please see below for the details of our policies. 

## Our Security Guarantee

Every time you buy from our site or register using your credit card number we ensure that your on-line credit and debit card transactions are secure by using industry-standard SSL (secure socket layer) encryption technology. In addition, to ensure there is absolutely minimal risk to you, we offer a guarantee for every purchase you make using a credit or debit card on our secure server. The guarantee we make to you is as follows: In the event of unauthorised use of your credit or debit card, most banks and card issuers either cover all of your potential charges or in some cases may limit your liability to just $50.00. At alamy.com, if your bank or card issuer does hold you liable we will cover this liability up to $50.00, provided that the unauthorised use of your credit or debit card resulted through no fault of your own and was for alamy.com purchases using our secure server. Please bear in mind that in the event of unauthorised use of your credit or debit card, you must still notify your card provider in accordance with its reporting rules and procedures. 

## Our Privacy Policy

At alamy.com we are committed to protecting your personal privacy and, in accordance with UK Data Protection law, we uphold strict security procedures for the storage, use and disclosure of your personal information. We have described below the personal information we may gather about you, the purposes we will hold it for and the limited categories of people whom we may disclose it to. Our Data Protection Registrar number is PX4517049. 

## What information do we collect and how may we use it?

When you register on the site we will ask for your name, your email address and a password. This enables us to send you information which we think you will find of interest, including our regular email newsletters and updates on any special offers or events coming up on the site. When you place orders with us, we need to know your name, email address, invoice and delivery address, telephone number, credit or debit card number and expiry date. This allows us to process and fulfill your orders and to notify you of your order status. We may provide some or all of this information to our partners or advisors for the purposes of completing or investigating a transaction with you or answering a question you raise with us.

We use information on your previous habits & purchases to personalise your shopping experience, and to show you products and promotions that we think will appeal to you. This information is collected by a “cookie” which is stored on your computer’s hard drive and enables us to automatically link our customers to their personalised accounts. If you want to, most web-browsers allow you to turn off the automatic acceptance of cookies on your PC. We also monitor the usage of our site and customer traffic patterns to help us improve the layout and functionality of the site.

When you enter a competition or other promotion, we may ask for your name, address and email address so we can administer the contest and notify winners. Your details will then be added to our mailing list for future offers and other information we may provide to our users. The information you provide to us may be transferred outside the United Kingdom for the purposes of operating our site or to maintain your customer account.

## Will we ever share your information?

No. Other than as described in this privacy policy, alamy.com will not sell, rent, share, trade or give away any of your personal information. Primarily we collect information about you in order to provide excellent customer service and a highly personalised experience of our site. We may share the personal information you provide with other members of our group of companies.

## What if I don’t want to receive any correspondence from you?

If you would rather not receive email, newsletters and other information please click on the appropriate box on the registration form when you initially register on the site or, if you change your mind at a later date, send an email to our customer services department at [nomail@alamy.com](mailto:nomail@alamy.com). 

Alternatively, you can write to us at Customer Services, alamy.com Limited, 6F Milton Park, Abingdon, Oxon, OX14 4RR.
